So our next exercise is called the scissor as you might know, or the correct Pilates term would be the single straight leg stretch.
Ok. That's a lot of Ss in there. So let's get started. Mark's going to lay all the way down. Beautiful.
From here you're going to bend your knees into your chest.
Again, that proximal position, curl the head, neck and shoulders up.
From here the legs go straight up in the air.
Reach the toes toward the ceiling.
If you have trouble straightening the back of your hamstrings flex the feet.
Yes.
From here grab onto your right ankle.
If you can't reach you can grab onto your right knee as well.
Scissor the left leg all the way down.
So you're going to use your exhale here as you pulse the leg in twice towards your face.
So your hand position should be onto your ankle.
If you're having trouble reaching your ankle you can come down to your calf or even back to the knee.
The most important thing is that your leg stays straight.
You don't want to pull in a bent leg.
You want to keep it long and lean.
So breathing is very important on this next exercise as well as the others.
You want to make sure that you're bell button scoops in in as you exhale.
So your belly button presses down, down and then you switch.
Belly button goes down, down and switch.
You compact those muscles into that breath so you're contracting those muscles as well as working them at the same time.
It creates a longer leaner muscle.
So you have exhale, whoo, whoo, and switch, navel scoops.
See your navel pushing in, in on that exhale.
Press.
Long legs.
Stretch and lengthen those legs.
Pulse.
Stay curled up.
So notice Mark's upper body is not moving here it's just the legs moving so you're getting those lower abs working.
Good.
Give me three more.
Three, and press, and two, straight out, press, last one, and one.
Draw the knees in towards the chest.
Relax head, neck and shoulders all the way down.
Take a rest.
The next clip with be the single, no the double straight leg stretch.